Hello everyone and welcome to English Pot.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine
and welcome everyone.
Today we've got an
elementary level lesson for you.
It's all about sending
things through the mail.
That's right. So maybe gifts, maybe
letters. We're going to the post office.
So why don't we jump
right into this dialogue?
Let's listen to it for the first
time and we'll be right back.
Hi, I would like to send this package
to China and these postcards as well.
Very well. You will need
some stamps for the
postcards and I need to
weigh that package too.
Great. How much is this going to cost?
Well, it depends. Do you want to send
a via priority, express or standard mail?
What's the difference?
Well, standard mail can
take up to 15 working days.
Priority is a bit faster and will
arrive in about 5 to 8 working days.
Express is the fastest but
it's also the most expensive.
It only takes three days and
you can track your package online.
I see. Well, there's no rush.
Please send it via priority mail.
Please be extra careful, the
contents of the package of fragile.
Alright, so pretty simple dialogue.
We want to send a package through the mail.
So why don't we take
a look at some of those
mail related terms in
language takeaway?
Language takeaway.
Alright, so the first item
we're going to talk about
in today's language takeaway
is something you can send.
It's called a postcard.
A postcard.
Okay, so very popular among
people who are traveling
and they want to send
a postcard back home.
That's right. So a postcard is
something that you usually buy
at a tourist destination like
Walt Disney World, for example.
And it has a picture on the
front and some words on the
back so you can write a letter
on the back of this picture.
So it's very simple. It's not really a
letter. You don't put it in an envelope.
You just write whatever you
want on the back of the postcard,
but you do have to put a
stamp on it in order to send it.
That's right. So stamp is our next word.
A stamp comes in different price ranges.
That means that some stamps are
more expensive than other stamps.
This is like money for the mail.
So you have to buy the stamps and in order to
prove that you have paid for the letter that
you want to send, you must place the stamps on
the letter on the envelope or on the postcard.
Right. So depending on the
size and weight, it costs more.
That's right. And usually
you lick a stamp to
place it on the card
so it doesn't fall off.
True. That's right. You got to lick it.
All right.
So as we talked about, a package can
be a letter at postcard, you place stamps
on it and we need to weigh the package
to know how much money we have to pay.
That's right. So sometimes
a package is very
heavy if it's filled with
books, for example.
Sometimes it's very light if it's
filled with clothes or feathers.
And so to find out how much something
weighs, we have to weigh it. This is a verb.
Okay. So this is a verb
right, two way. So you want to
know how many kilos or how
many pounds this item has.
Right. So we could say it weighs
a lot or how much do you weigh?
Okay. It's like this. Very good.
All right. Moving on, we have the different
types of mailing speeds, I guess. Right.
So we saw three via priority
mail, express mail or standard mail.
So let's go in parts. Let's go
with the first one via priority mail.
Priority is fast. It means priority
is something that's important.
So I have many priorities at work.
This means they're important.
Very important. So this
letter has a certain importance.
It's a little bit more important
than, for example, the other letters.
That's right. But express is
the most important, the fastest.
So to something that's
expressed is fast, like
an express way is the
fast highway, express mail.
Okay. So express
mail is the fastest.
And now the normal
cheapest mail is standard mail.
Standard. So the word standard usually
means the average or the normal mail.
And in this case, it usually
takes the longest. Okay.
So obviously standard
mail is the cheapest, express
mail is the most expensive
because it's the fastest.
That's right. So we've got all those
speeds now. Let's listen again to
today's dialogue and try and listen
for the words we just talked about.
And we'll be back in a moment to
talk about some important phrases.
Hi. I would like to send this package
to China and these postcards as well.
Very well. You will need
some stamps for the
postcards and I need to
weigh that package too.
Great. How much is this going to cost?
Well, it depends. Do you want to send
a via priority, express, or standard mail?
What's the difference?
Well, standard mail can
take up to 15 working days.
Priority is a bit faster and will
arrive in about 5 to 8 working days.
Express is the fastest, but
it's also the most expensive.
It only takes three days and
you can track your package online.
I see. Well, there's no rush.
Please send it via priority mail.
Please be extra careful the
contents of the package of fragile.
All right. We're back.
So now let's take a
look at three key
phrases on Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder. All right.
So the first phrase today
is one that I like to use a lot.
We say, it depends. Okay. How much
is this going to cost? Well, it depends.
Okay. So the phrase
could be, it depends.
So it depends. When
do you usually use this?
Okay. If you ask me a
question, I can have one
answer, but maybe there's
another possible answer.
For example, what are you
going to wear tomorrow, Marco?
It depends if it rains or not.
Okay. It depends. If it rains, I
will wear a raincoat. If it's
sunny, I will wear a normal coat.
So it depends means there is
a situation or a circumstance
that might change. And if it
does, my answer will change.
Right. So it is a
conditional. It depends.
For example, I can ask you,
what are you going to eat tonight?
It depends. If I exercise, I'm
going to have a hamburger.
And if I don't exercise,
I'll have a salad. Nice. Okay.
So it depends. Now we have
another phrase when they were
talking about how long it's
going to take to mail something.
He said standard mail can
take up to 15 working days.
So we have this little
phrase there up to up to.
So up to when you hear this, these
two words together, that's an indication.
It's a sign that we're talking
about the maximum, the most.
Okay. So tomorrow, the temperature
might go up to 24 degrees Celsius.
Okay. So the temperature maximum will reach
24. It could be maybe 22, 21, but not 25.
Not 20, no, because up to means the top.
So you're usually dealing
with numbers, right?
For example, this coat
can cost up to $150.
Wow. So the most I will spend is $150.
So sometimes you have a number like this
when we're talking about sending a package.
We can send packages that way up to
10 kilos, not more than 10 kilos, though.
Okay. Very good. And now for
our last phrase to close off the
dialogue, the guy said, well,
you know what, there's no rush.
There's no rush. No rush. There's no rush.
Okay. Well, the first word we want
to look at here is the word rush.
In this case, we're talking about
sending a package and the postcard, right?
So does this person want it to arrive fast?
He says, no, no, there's no rush.
Let's send it standard. It's cheaper.
Okay. So maybe your friend is like,
"Come on, we're going to be late.
" And you're like,
no, there's no rush.
There's no rush.
We have one hour before
the movie starts calm down.
Okay. So you're not in a hurry.
No, there's no rush. Slow down.
It's okay. This is a good
one to talk about with friends.
Or if you're working on a project and
work, you say, listen, there's no rush.
Take your time. Okay. Very good.
So let's go back to our dialogue.
Let's listen to it for the very last time.
And we'll be back in a bit.
Hi. I would like to send this package
to China and these postcards as well.
Very well. You will need
some stamps for the
postcards and I need to
weigh that package too.
Great. How much is this going to cost?
Well, it depends. Do you want to send
a via priority, express, or standard mail?
What's the difference?
Well, standard mail can
take up to 15 working days.
Priority is a bit faster and will arrive
in about five to eight working days.
Express is the fastest, but
it's also the most expensive.
It only takes three days and
you can track your package online.
I see. Well, there's no rush.
Please send it via priority mail.
Please be extra careful, the
contents of the package of fragile.
All right. We're back so
now. Catherine, do you usually
send postcards when you
are abroad, when you travel?
Yes, I love postcards.
And actually, I have some
friends who have an
amazing postcard collection.
Oh, really? But it's not normal postcards.
They find the most ugly
postcards and they buy them and
they write sibling notes and
they send them to themselves.
Oh, really? I have the
tradition of always sending my
parents and my grandparents
a postcard when I'm abroad.
That's so sweet. So they have a
collection of all the places you've been.
Yeah. So all the time wherever
I am, the first thing that
I try to do if I'm in a cool
place, I send them a postcard.
And sometimes if I'm in a country in
various cities and there are some nice
things in, for example, two or three
cities, I'll send them three postcards.
That's awesome. So
do they have a book at
home with all these
postcards? Yeah, they do.
So, you know, I just send them a little
thing, how I'm doing and how great it is and
wish you could be here, you know, little
notes and then they have all the collection.
It's really cool because that
way I've actually kept track a
little bit of what year and
what date I was in certain places.
Oh, wow. Well, it's also nice because postcards
you don't need to write a very long note. There's
no space. You just write a short note. You say hi.
How's the weather? Miss you wish you were here.
Right. Okay. So that's all the time
we have for today, but let us know if
you've had any inconveniences at
the post office. I actually had one once.
I couldn't send batteries
through the mail, but really
have acid apparently. So
it's very difficult to send.
So maybe you've had a
situation like this before.
Let us know English pot.com. We'll
see you guys there. Bye, everyone. Bye.